Guide to the Rudolf Carnap Papers, 1904-2007 ASP.1974.01
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Correspondence with Individuals, 1921-1970; XXI.
  - Dörpfeld, Wilhelm, 1933-1937 (Box 102, Folder 30)
  - Lowenberg, Erna, 1967-1970 (Box 102, Folder 31)
  - Bergemann, Eva, 1948 and 1952 (Box 102, Folder 32)
  - Lowenberg, Erna, 1963-1967 (Box 102, Folder 33)
  - Roh, Franz, 1950, 1964-1965 (Box 102, Folder 34)
  - Sobler, Benedict and Raya, 1963-1964 (Box 102, Folder 35)
  - Zohn, Roberta, 1970 (Box 102, Folder 36)
  - Bridgman, P.W., 1934-1942 (Box 102, Folder 38)
  - Dewey, John, 1934-1943 (Box 102, Folder 39)
  - Einstein, Albert, 1940, 1949-1951 (Box 102, Folder 40)
  - Fraenkel, Abraham H., 1934-1949 (Box 102, Folder 41)
  - Frank, Philipp, 1956 (Box 102, Folder 42)
  - Gödel, Kurt, Allgemein, 1928-1940 (Box 102, Folder 43)
  - Goodman, Nelson, 1937-1941 (Box 102, Folder 44)
  - Guérard, Albert, 1937-1949 (Box 102, Folder 45)
  - Hempel, Peter, Allgemein, 1935-1955 (Box 102, Folder 46)
  - Morris, Charles, 1956-1958 (Box 102, Folder 47)
  - Morris, Charles, 1960-1968 (Box 102, Folder 48)
  - Naess, Arne, 1963-1969 (Box 102, Folder 49)
  - Neurath, Otto, 1935-1936 (Box 102, Folder 50)
  - Neurath, Otto, 1937 (Box 102, Folder 51)
  - Neurath, Otto, 1935-1936 (Box 102, Folder 52)
  - Neurath, Otto, 1938-1939 (Box 102, Folder 53)
  - Neurath, Otto, 1938 (Box 102, Folder 54)
  - Neurath, Otto, 1940-1945 (Box 102, Folder 55)
  - Neurath, Otto, 1941-1946 (Box 102, Folder 56)
  - Neurath, Otto, 1934-1943 (Box 102, Folder 57)
  - Ogden, Charles Kay, 1934-1936 (Box 102, Folder 58)
  - Popper, Karl Raimund, 1932-1950 (Box 102, Folder 59)
  - Quine, Willard Van Orman, 1934-1937 (Box 102, Folder 60)
  - Quine, Willard Van Orman, 1930-1938 (Box 102, Folder 61)
  - Quine, Willard Van Orman, Discussions, 1943-1954 (Box 102, Folder 62)
  - Quine, Willard Van Orman, Discussions, 1940-1947 (Box 102, Folder 63)
  - Reichenbach, Hans, 1924-1927, and 1935 (Box 102, Folder 64)
  - Reichenbach, Hans, 1937-1950 (Box 102, Folder 65)
  - Reichenbach, Hans, 1927-1933 (Box 102, Folder 66)
  - Rundbrief Prag, 1932-1934 (Box 102, Folder 67)
  - Russell, Bertrand, 1921-1941 (Box 102, Folder 68)
  - Russell Seminar Chicago, 1939-1940 (Box 102, Folder 69)
  - Schlick, Moritz, 1934-1936 (Box 102, Folder 70)
  - Scholz, Heinrich, 1950-1956 (Box 102, Folder 71)
  - Scholz, Heinrich, 1923-1932 (Box 102, Folder 72)
  - Sobocinski, Boleslav (Box 102, Folder 73)
  - Strauss, Martin, 1937-1946 (Box 102, Folder 74)
  - Strauss, Martin, 1937-1939 (Box 102, Folder 75)
  - Waismann, Friedrich, 1929-1930 (Box 102, Folder 76)
  - Wittgenstein, Ludwig, 1927 (Box 102, Folder 77)
  - Wittgenstein, Ludwig, 1930-1932, and 1956 (Box 102, Folder 78)
- Card Files, XXII.
  This series contains filing cards recording bibliographic entries, reading notes, subject indexes, and addresses.
  - Bibliography in Probability: Reading Notes in Shorthand, A-E, ca. 630 Cards (Box 103, Folder 1)
  - Bibliography in Probability: Reading Notes in Shorthand, F-M, ca. 690 Cards (Box 103, Folder 2)
  - Bibliography in Probability: Reading Notes in Shorthand, N-Z, ca. 630 Cards (Box 103, Folder 3)
  - General Bibliography: Reading Notes in Shorthand, A-C, ca. 860 Cards (Box 103, Folder 4)
  - Bibliography in Science Fiction, Annotated in Shorthand, ca. 90 Cards (Box 105, Folder 1)
  - Bibliography International Language, Annotated in Shorthand, ca. 780 Cards (Box 105, Folder 2)
  - Subject Index to Bibliography in Probability, Annotated in Shorthand, ca. 50 Cards (Box 105, Folder 3)
  - Terminology, Annotated in Shorthand, ca. 437 Cards (Box 105, Folder 4)
  - Subject Index to General Bibliography, Annotated in Shorthand, ca. 340 Cards (Box 105, Folder 5)
  - Bibliography of Carnaps Writings, Annotated in Shorthand, ca. 340 Cards (Box 105, Folder 6)
  - "For Filing," 5 Cards (Box 105, Folder 7)
  - Addresses with Biographical Notes, Shorthand, 970 Cards (Box 105, Folder 8)
  - Reading Notes Shorthand A-F: ca. 1640 cards (Box 113, Folder 1)
  - Reading Notes Shorthand G-L: ca. 1320 cards (Box 113, Folder 2)
  - Reading Notes Shorthand M-R: ca. 1330 cards (Box 113, Folder 3)
  - Reading Notes Shorthand S-Z: ca. 1200 cards (Box 113, Folder 4)
  - Addresses America (Chicago), with Biographical Notes, Shorthand; Chicago Students, with Biographical Notes, 1933-1954 (Box 114, Folder 1.1)
  - Addresses America (California), with Biographical Notes, Shorthand, 1954-1970 (Box 114, Folder 1.2)
  - Addresses Europe with Biographical Notes, Shorthand, up to 1952: ca. 740 cards (Box 114, Folder 2)
- An Axiom System of Inductive Logic (AS): Drafts and Dittos, 1959-1965; XXIII.
  "An Axiom System of Inductive Logic" later evolved into "A Basic System of Inductive Logic." Carnap circulated a draft of the Axiom System (AS) privately for review.
  - An Axiom System of Inductive Logic, First Part, First Version, 1959 (Box 106, Folder 1)
  - An Axiom System of Inductive Logic, Second Part, First Version, 1960 (Box 106, Folder 2)
  - An Axiom System of Inductive Logic, Third Part, First Version (incomplete), 1961 (Box 106, Folder 3)
  - An Axiom System of Inductive Logic, Chapters 12 and 13 (Box 106, Folder 4)
  - An Axiom System of Inductive Logic, pp. 411-503 (Box 106, Folder 5)
  - An Axiom System of Inductive Logic, Chapters 17, 12, 13, 14, 15, 16, 18 (Items 1-6) (Box 106, Folder 6a)
  - An Axiom System of Inductive Logic, Fragments (Items 7-11), 1964 (Box 106, Folder 6b)
  - An Axiom System of Inductive Logic, §18: Lambda-Families (Item 12) (Box 106, Folder 6c)
  - An Axiom System of Inductive Logic, Chapters 1-13, without Chapters 1-5, 7, 1960 (Box 106, Folder 7)
  - An Axiom System of Inductive Logic, Part V: Chapters 17-19 (Box 106, Folder 8)
  - An Axiom System of Inductive Logic: 14. The Attribute Space (Items 1-2), 1963 (Box 106, Folder 9a)
  - An Axiom System of Inductive Logic: 15. On Methodological Rules (Item 3), 1963 (Box 106, Folder 9b)
  - An Axiom System of Inductive Logic: 16. The Analogy Influence (Item 4), 1963 (Box 106, Folder 9c)
  - Skeleton for AS, Chapters 1-19 (Items 1-7), 1959-1960 (Box 106, Folder 10a)
  - Skeleton for AS, Chapters 1-19 (Items 8-10), 1959-1961 (Box 106, Folder 10b)
  - Skeleton for AS, Chapters 1-19 (Items 11-13), 1960-1961 (Box 106, Folder 10c)
  - Skeleton for AS, Chapters 1-19 (Items 14-16), 1961 (Box 106, Folder 10d)
  - Skeleton for AS, Chapters 1-19 (Items 17-19), 1961-1962 (Box 106, Folder 10e)
  - Skeleton for AS, Chapters 1-19 (Items 20-22), 1961-1964 (Box 106, Folder 10f)
  - Skeleton for AS, Chapters 1-19 (Item 23), 1960-1965 (Box 106, Folder 10g)
  - Skeleton for AS, Chapters 1-19 (Item 24), 1960-1965 (Box 106, Folder 10h)
  - An Axiom System of Inductive Logic: Introduction, 1964 (Box 106, Folder 11)
  - An Axiom System of Inductive Logic, Chapter 17: Some Special Kind of Families, 1963-1964 (Box 106, Folder 12)
  - An Axiom System of Inductive Logic, Chapter 18: Lambda-Families (Item 1a), 1963-1964 (Box 106, Folder 13a)
  - An Axiom System of Inductive Logic, Chapter 18: The Lambda-Families (Item 1b), 1963-1964 (Box 106, Folder 13b)
  - An Axiom System of Inductive Logic, Chapter 19: The Limit Axioms, 1963-1965 (Box 106, Folder 14)
  - An Axiom System of Inductive Logic, Chapters 1-13 (old uncorrected): 1. Introductory Remarks, 1959 (Box 106, Folder 15)
  - An Axiom System of Inductive Logic, Chapters 1-13 (old uncorrected): 2. The Basic Axioms (Box 106, Folder 16)
  - An Axiom System of Inductive Logic, Chapters 1-13 (old uncorrected): 3. Models (Box 106, Folder 17)
  - An Axiom System of Inductive Logic, Chapters 1-13 (old uncorrected): 4. Predicate Languages (Box 106, Folder 18)
  - An Axiom System of Inductive Logic, Chapters 1-13 (old uncorrected): 5. A-Postulates (Box 106, Folder 19)
  - An Axiom System of Inductive Logic, Chapters 1-13 (old uncorrected): 6. Sublanguages, 1960 (Box 106, Folder 20)
  - An Axiom System of Inductive Logic, Chapters 1-13 (old uncorrected): 7. Regularity (Box 106, Folder 21)
  - An Axiom System of Inductive Logic, Chapters 1-13 (old uncorrected): 8. General Concept of Regularity (Omitted in BS) (Box 106, Folder 22)
  - An Axiom System of Inductive Logic, Chapters 1-13 (old uncorrected): 9. Coherent C (Box 106, Folder 23)
  - An Axiom System of Inductive Logic, Chapters 1-13 (old uncorrected): 10. Symmetric C, 1961 (Box 106, Folder 24)
  - An Axiom System of Inductive Logic, Chapters 1-13 (old uncorrected): 11. One Family (Box 106, Folder 25)
  - An Axiom System of Inductive Logic, Chapters 1-13 (old uncorrected): 12. Representative Functions for Symmetric M and C (Box 106, Folder 26)
  - An Axiom System of Inductive Logic, Chapters 1-13 (old uncorrected): 12. MS (Box 106, Folder 27)
  - An Axiom System of Inductive Logic, Chapters 1-13 (old uncorrected): 12. Cj (Box 106, Folder 28)
  - An Axiom System of Inductive Logic, Chapters 1-13 (old uncorrected): 13. Instantatial Relevance (Box 106, Folder 29)
- Publications, Dissertations, and Lecture Notes, 1910-1970; XXIV.
  This series covers a range of Carnap's writings and publications projects, including some dissertations written by others in subseries 1. Subseries 2 features probablity papers and notes, authored by Carnap and others. Subseries 3 comprises Schilpp material, notes, and printing-proofs for various works. Finally, subseries 4 contains correspondence with publishers, drafts and page-roofs, lecture notes, Frege seminar notes, and the handwritten letter by Bertrand Russell summarizing his work "Principia Mathematica."
  - Dissertations, 1.
    - Oppacher, Franz, 1955 and 1968 (Box 107, Folder 1)
    - Oppacher, Franz: "Das zeitgenössische Problem der Analytizität," Dissertation, 1965 (Box 107, Folder 2)
    - Lanter, Hal: "An Analysis of Scientific Laws," Dissertation, 1967 (Box 107, Folder 3)
    - Bohnert, Herbert: "The Interpretation of Theory," Dissertation, 1961 (Box 107, Folder 4)
    - Vetter, Hermann: "Wahrscheinlichkeit und logischer Spielraum", 1965 (Box 107, Folder 5)
    - Champawat, Narayan: "On the Concept of an Observation Language", 1969 (Box 107, Folder 6)
  - Probability Papers, 2.
    - Burks, Arthur W.: "Cause, Change, and Reason," Typescript, Chapters V & VI, 1963-1964 (Box 107, Folder 7)
    - From AS, Chapter 18, 1970 (Box 107, Folder 8)
    - "Uncertain Evidence": Jeffrey and Matthew Notes, 1966 (Box 107, Folder 9)
    - Ms. "Uncertain Evidence," Gordon Matthews, 1966-1968 (Box 107, Folder 10)
    - "Uncertain Evidence," the Second Rule, 1968 (Box 107, Folder 11)
    - "Uncertain Evidence", 1966 (Box 107, Folder 12)
    - "Uncertain Evidence," the First Rule, 1967-1968 (Box 107, Folder 13)
    - Article 1: "Inductive Logic and Rational Decisions", 1969-1970 (Box 107, Folder 14)
    - The Logical Foundations of Probability: Preface to the 2nd Edition, 1962-1963 (Box 107, Folder 15)
    - "Inductive Logic and Inductive Intuition," International Colloquium in the Philosophy of Science, London 1965: Reprint, 1968 (Box 107, Folder 16)
    - "On Rules of Acceptance": Discussion Remarks on Kyburg, Bar-Hillel, and Salmon, London 1965, Typescript, 1965-1966 (Box 107, Folder 17)
    - "The Aim of Inductive Logic:" Annotated Reprint, 1962 (Box 107, Folder 18)
    - "Discussion: Variety, Analogy, and Periodicity in Inductive Logic," Annotated Reprint, 1963 (Box 107, Folder 19)
    - "Probability and Content Measure," Reprint, 1966 (Box 107, Folder 20)
    - "Ein neues Axiomensystem für die c-Funktionen": Stegmüller, Anhang Induktive Logik, Galley Proofs, 1958 (Box 107, Folder 21)
    - "Degree of Order in a Classification": Typscript and Notes, 1952 and 1963 (Box 107, Folder 22)
    - Notes on Probability and Induction: Seminar UCLA, 1955-1960 (Box 107, Folder 23)
  - Schilpp Material, Notes, and Printing-Proofs for Various Works, 3.
    - "Probability and Induction": Reply 25 for Schilpp-Volume (Box 107, Folder 24)
    - "An Axiom System for Inductive Logic": Reply 26 for Schilpp-Volume (Box 107, Folder 25)
    - Replies 27-31 for Schilpp-Volume (Box 107, Folder 26)
    - Supplementary Bibliogaphy: Galleys and Typescript, 1960-1962 (Box 107, Folder 27)
    - 11. "Robert Feys on Modalities" (Box 107, Folder 28)
    - Bibliography of Rudolf Carnap, 1959-1962 (Box 107, Folder 29)
    - "My Views on Ontological Problems of Existence," Reply 4 Schilpp-Volume (Box 107, Folder 30)
    - "Modal Logic": Reply 9 for Schilpp-Volume, 1962 (Box 107, Folder 31)
    - "My Conception of Semantics": Reply 10 for Schilpp-Volume (Box 107, Folder 32)
    - Reply to Hempel, 1961 (Box 107, Folder 33)
    - "Theoretical Concepts in Science": Typescripts, 1954 and 1962 (Box 107, Folder 34)
    - "Remarks on Physicalism and Related Topics: Discussion with Wilfrid Sellars", December 1954 (Box 107, Folder 35)
    - Vorwort Der logische Aufbau der Welt, 1961 (Box 107, Folder 36)
    - "Notes on Semantics," UCLA Seminar, Typescripts, 1936 and 1955-1960 (Box 107, Folder 37)
    - Einführung in die symbolische Logik: Corrected Page-Proofs (Item 1), 1959-1960 (Box 109, Folder 1a)
    - Einführung in die symbolische Logik: Corrected Page-Proofs (Item 2a), 1959-1960 (Box 109, Folder 1b)
    - Einführung in die symbolische Logik: Corrected Page-Proofs (Item 2b), 1959-1960 (Box 109, Folder 1c)
    - Einführung in die symbolische Logik: Corrected Page-Proofs (Item 2c), 1959-1960 (Box 109, Folder 1d)
    - Meaning and Necessity, Chicago: Page-Proofs, 1947 (Box 109, Folder 2)
    - Formulization of Logic: Page-Proofs (Box 109, Folder 3)
    - Introduction to Semantics: Typescript and Page-Proofs (Item 1), 1941 (Box 109, Folder 4a)
    - Introduction to Semantics: Typescript and Page-Proofs (Item 2), 1941 (Box 109, Folder 4b)
    - The Logical Syntax of Language: Page-Proofs (Box 109, Folder 5)
    - On the Application of Inductive Logic: Page-Proofs (Box 109, Folder 6)
    - Logical Foundation of the Unity of Science: Page-Proofs (Box 109, Folder 7)
    - Review of Quine's A System of Logistic: Page-Proofs, 1935 (Box 109, Folder 8)
    - "Die Methode der logichen Analyse": Page-Proofs (Box 109, Folder 9)
    - "Die logizistische Grundlegung der Mathematik": Page-Proofs, 1931 (Box 109, Folder 10)
    - "Die Mathematik als Zweig der Logik": Page-Proofs (Box 109, Folder 11)
    - Excerpts from Schilpp-Volume: Mimeos, 1962 (Box 109, Folder 12)
    - The Philosophy of Rudolf Carnap: 2nd Proof, (Items 1-2) (Box 109, Folder 13a)
    - The Philosophy of Rudolf Carnap: 2nd Proof, (Item 3a) (Box 109, Folder 13b)
    - The Philosophy of Rudolf Carnap: 2nd Proof, (Item 3b) (Box 109, Folder 13c)
    - Replies I., Schilpp-Volume (Box 109, Folder 14)
    - Replies II., Schilpp-Volume (Box 109, Folder 15)
    - Replies III., Schilpp-Volume (Box 109, Folder 16)
    - Introductory Remarks to Replies of Schilpp-Volume (Box 109, Folder 17)
    - Mimeographed Copies of "Contents" from Schilpp-Volume (Box 109, Folder 18)
    - Reply: 1: "Charles Morris on Pragmatism and Logical Empiricism" (Box 109, Folder 19)
    - Reply 2: "Robert S. Cohen on Dialectical Materialism vs. Empiricism" (Box 109, Folder 20)
    - Reply 3: "Philipp Frank and V. Brushlinsky on Positivism, Metaphysics, and Marxism" (Box 109, Folder 21)
    - Reply 5: "Paul Henle on Meaning and Verifiability" (Box 109, Folder 22)
    - Reply 9: "My Conceptions of the Logic of Modalities" (Box 109, Folder 23)
    - Reply 10: "My Conception of Semantics" (Box 109, Folder 24)
    - Reply 14: "Richard Martin on Semantics" (Box 109, Folder 25)
    - Reply 12: "John Myhill on Modal Logic and Semantics" (Box 109, Folder 26)
    - Reply 13: "Donald Davidson on Modalities and Semantics" (Box 109, Folder 27)
    - Reply 16: Herbert G. Bohnert on Definitions and Analyticity (Box 109, Folder 28)
    - Reply 18: "E.W. Beth on Constructed Language Systems" (Box 109, Folder 29)
    - Reply 20: "Yehoshua Bar-Hillel on Linguistics and Metatheory" (Box 109, Folder 30)
    - Reply 23: "Adolf Grünbaum on the Philosophy of Space and Time" (Box 109, Folder 31)
    - § 24: "Carl G. Hempel on Scientific Theories" (Box 109, Folder 32)
    - Reply 27: "John G. Kemeny on Probability and Induction" (Box 109, Folder 33)
    - Reply 32: "Abraham Kaplan on Value Judgements" (Box 109, Folder 34)
    - Carnap, Logik, 2. Auflage: Page-Proofs, 1959 (Box 109, Folder 35)
    - Logische Syntax der Sprache: Page-Proofs, 1968 (Box 109, Folder 36)
    - Einführung in die symbolische Logik: Page-Proofs, 1968 (Box 109, Folder 37)
    - The Continuum of Inductive Methods: Page-Proofs, 1952 (Box 109, Folder 38-40)
    - Induktive Logik und Wahrscheinlichkeit: Page-Proofs, 1958-1959 (Box 109, Folder 41-42)
  - Correspondence with Publishers, Page-Proofs, and Seminar and Lecture Notes, 4.
    - Politische Rundbriefe 1-15 (Items 1-13), 1918 (Box 110, Folder 1a)
    - Politische Rundbriefe 16-33 (Items 14-27), 1918-1919 (Box 110, Folder 1b)
    - Politische Rundbriefe 34-55 (Items 28-46), 1919 (Box 110, Folder 1c)
    - Typescripts and Lectures with some Correspondence, 1934-1940 (Box 110, Folder 2)
    - Proof Sheets, Early Articles and Notes (Items 1-9), 1929-1931 (Box 110, Folder 3a)
    - Proof Sheets, Early Articles: "Mein Vortrag Königsberg" (Items 10-12), September 1930 (Box 110, Folder 3b)
    - Proof Sheets, Early Articles (Items 13-21), 1930-1931 (Box 110, Folder 3c)
    - Proof Sheets, Early Articles: "Die physikalische Sprache als Universalsprache der Wissenschaft" (Item 22), 1930-1932 (Box 110, Folder 3d)
    - Proof Sheets, Early Articles (Items 23-35), 1930-1932 (Box 110, Folder 3e)
    - Proof Sheets, Early Articles: "Die Psychologie in physikalischer Sprache (Item 36), 1930-1932 (Box 110, Folder 3f)
    - Early Manuscripts and Reviews (Items 1-4), 1933 (Box 110, Folder 4a)
    - Early Manuscripts and Reviews (Items 5-10), 1931-1934 (Box 110, Folder 4b)
    - Early Manuscripts: "Theoretische Fragen und praktische Entscheidungen" (Item 11), 1933 (Box 110, Folder 4c)
    - Early Manuscripts: "Gibt es nicht-prüfbare Voraussetzungen der Wissenschaft" (Item 12), 1935 (Box 110, Folder 4d)
    - Correspondence with Publishers, Galleys to Articles, Notes (Items 1-10), 1921-1935 (Box 110, Folder 5a)
    - Correspondence with Publishers, Galleys to Articles, Notes (Items 11-43), 1921-1935 (Box 110, Folder 5b)
    - Correspondence with Publishers, Galleys to Articles, Notes (Items 44-56), 1921-1935 (Box 110, Folder 5c)
    - "Für Vol. II, Probability, Chapters X-XIII (Items 1-24), 1941-1952 (Box 110, Folder 6a)
    - "Für Vol. II, Probability, Chapters X-XIII (Items 25-47), 1941-1952 (Box 110, Folder 6b)
    - Lectures in Europe (Items 1-17), 1931-1937 (Box 110, Folder 7a)
    - Lectures in Europe (Items 18-29), 1929-1937 (Box 110, Folder 7b)
    - Lectures in Europe (Items 30-42), 1929-1933 (Box 110, Folder 7c)
    - Lectures in Europe (Items 43-54), 1922-1933 (Box 110, Folder 7d)
    - Lectures in U.S., 1934-1947 (Box 110, Folder 8)
    - Seminar Notes (Items 1-4), 1930-1938 (Box 110, Folder 9a)
    - Seminar Notes (Items 5-6), 1926-1945 (Box 110, Folder 9b)
    - Seminar Notes (Item 7), 1929-1934 (Box 110, Folder 9c)
    - Seminar Notes (Items 8-16), 1929-1942 (Box 110, Folder 9d)
    - Russell Letter (Box 111, Folder 1)
    - Frege Seminar Notes: Begriffsschrift/Logik in der Mathematik (Original), 1910-1913 (Box 111, Folder 2a)
    - Frege Seminar Notes: Begriffsschrift/Logik in der Mathematik (Transcription) (Box 111, Folder 2b)
    - Frege Seminar Notes (Box 111, Folder 3)
    - Frege: "Über Sinn und Bedeutung", 1943 and 1962 (Box 111, Folder 4)
    - Pasquinelli, Alberto: Italian Translation of "The Continuum of Inductive Methods", 1962-1970 (Box 111, Folder 5)
    - Ms. "Philosophy and Logical Analysis," Lecture, 1936 (Box 111, Folder 6)
    - "Theoretische Fragen und praktische Entscheidungen", 1933 and 1939 (Box 111, Folder 7)
    - Felix Meiner Verlag, Publisher, 1958-1966 (Box 111, Folder 8)
    - Springer Verlag, Publisher, 1962-1966 (Box 111, Folder 9)
    - "Philosophical Foundations of Physics," Lecture I (Item 1), 1958 (Box 111, Folder 10a)
    - Philosophical Foundations of Physics," Lecture II (Item 2), 1958 (Box 111, Folder 10b)
    - Philosophical Foundations of Physics," Lecture III (Item 3-4), 1958 (Box 111, Folder 10c)
    - Philosophical Foundations of Physics," Lecture IV (Item 5), 1958 (Box 111, Folder 10d)
    - Philosophical Foundations of Physics," Lecture V (Item 6), 1958 (Box 111, Folder 10e)
    - Philosophical Foundations of Physics," Lecture VI (Item 7), 1958 (Box 111, Folder 10f)
    - Philosophical Foundations of Physics," Lecture VII (Item 8), 1958 (Box 111, Folder 10g)
    - "Philosophical Foundations of Physics," Lecture VIII (Item 1), 1958-1962 (Box 111, Folder 11a)
    - "Philosophical Foundations of Physics," Lecture IX (Item 2), 1958-1962 (Box 111, Folder 11b)
    - "Philosophical Foundations of Physics," Lecture X (Item 3), 1958-1962 (Box 111, Folder 11c)
    - "Philosophical Foundations of Physics," Lecture XI (Item 4), 1958-1962 (Box 111, Folder 11d)
    - "Philosophical Foundations of Physics," Lecture XIII (Item 5), 1958-1962 (Box 111, Folder 11e)
    - "Philosophical Foundations of Physics," Lecture XII (Item 1), 1958-1962 (Box 111, Folder 12a)
    - "Philosophical Foundations of Physics," Lecture XII (Item 2), 1958-1962 (Box 111, Folder 12b)
    - "Philosophical Foundations of Physics," Lecture XIV (Item 1), 1959-1965 (Box 111, Folder 13a)
    - "Philosophical Foundations of Physics," Lecture XV (Item 2), 1959-1965 (Box 111, Folder 13b)
    - Philosophical Foundations of Physics (Items 3-8), 1959-1965 (Box 111, Folder 13c)
    - "Philosophical Foundations of Physics," Additions and Insertions (Items 1-5), 1963-1965 (Box 111, Folder 14a)
    - Bertrand Russell 3. Trial, Clippings, 1940-1943 (Box 111, Folder 15)
    - Clippings, Notes, and Marginalia Found in Carnap's Books (Box 111, Folder 16)
    - Frege Offprint "On the Foundations of Geometry." (Box 111, Folder 17)
- Supplementary Carnap Material with Varied Provenance, 1913-2007; XXVI.
  This material was received after the original acquisition of the Carnap Papers, mostly by donation or exchange of photocopies with other repositories. Besides correspondence with, among others, Flitner, Dingler, Quine, Gödel, and Neurath, some additional formats can be found, such as an anecdote by Peter Achinstein about a meeting with Carnap and others, manuscript drafts by others, and a book list of Carnap's library. In some cases, a sheet informing about the provenance of the material was included at the beginning of the file folder. This sheet carries its own number and is included in the total item count.
  - Correspondence between Herbert A. Simon and Rudolf Carnap; donated by Herbert A. Simon; 3 items, 1937 (Box 115, Folder 1)
  - Typed notes entitled "Carnap, Notes for Introduction," "The Ten Virtues of Good Scientific Theories," and typed lecture notes entitled "Introduction to Analytic Philosophy," by unknown author; donated by Thomas Oberdan. (Box 115, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence between Carnap and Wilhelm Flitner, 71 items, 1913-1969 (Box 115, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence between Carnap and Hugo Dingler, 37 items, 1920-1953 (Box 115, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence between Carnap and W.V. Quine, 58 items, 1939-1964 (Box 115, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence between Carnap and W.V. Quine, 80 items, 1932-1939 (Box 115, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence between Carnap and Otto Neurath, 69 items, 1934-1948 (Box 115, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence between Carnap and Kurt Gödel, 13 items, 1929-1939 (Box 115, Folder 8)
  - Kurt Gödel: "Is Mathematics Syntax of Language?" Copies of two drafts of a paper by Kurt Gödel intended to be included in Schilpp, The Philosophy of Rudolf Carnap. Due to Gödel's dissatisfaction with it, the paper was never finished; 3 items. (Box 115, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence between Carnap and Heinrich Behmann, 26 items, 1922-1954 (Box 115, Folder 10)